our first speaker today is john kiriakou
john is an author and a brave
whistleblower who confirmed that the cia
was torturing people
accused of being terrorists following
the 9 11 attacks
john take it away
hi everybody thanks so much for
inviting me
um i want to talk just a little bit for
a minute about the actual date of
september 11th 2001. i was at cia
headquarters like uh you know so many
thousands of other people were
and
the one thing that sticks in my head
from that day
was thinking
about al qaeda my god do you have any
idea
what you've done do you have any idea
how many innocent people are going to be
killed now because of this
i mean certainly
i knew what my government was capable of
doing
i just assumed that others knew what the
american government was capable of doing
too you know it's no accident
that the washington dc area
now has the highest concentration of
anywhere in america and it's because
those military contractors
and intelligence community contractors
saw their opportunity and they got rich
they got rich because they knew that we
would enter into what turned out to be a
permanent wartime economy
i think that something even worse than
that that came out of september 11th
was the number of precedents that we
sent
that made it okay
to kill innocent people
it was okay to develop a drone program
it was okay for the military to cross
borders and indiscriminately drop bombs
or fire rockets
and then when we kill entire families at
weddings or funerals just say well there
was a terrorist there
we knew what we were doing take our word
for it
if you could see the intelligence that
we have you would know that we did the
right thing well i saw the intelligence
that they had and it was all a lie it
was all made up
the problem with that
besides the obvious
is that many americans believe those
lies and now 20 years later
continue to believe those lies
we've gone from the hunt for al qaeda
the hunt for bin laden to the hunt for
saddam hussein to the hunt for isis
and now there's this group isis k
in afghanistan and when we send drones
to to blow up the leadership of isis k
and then kill an entire family including
seven children five of whom were under
the age of five we're again told take
our word for it we know what we're doing
there were terrorists there
we can't if the rest of the country
didn't learn its lesson after 9 11
at least we've learned our lesson and
it's up to us it's especially up
[Music]
john you're breaking up
take the mantle
of the begin the change of public
opinion
is that any better
yes
you might shut off your video to make
sure it doesn't happen again
okay i'm gonna do that i'm gonna try
that right now
so it's it's up to the young people of
our country to make sure that it doesn't
happen again it is it is the young
people who can take these leadership
positions
for peace
and
justice and one of the things that's
been so important to me in my
posts yeah a
career
has been we must be relentless about a
whole archipelago of of secret prisons
that we're not rendering prisoners to
third countries to face torture that
they might not face here in the united
states but we can't take their word for
it
because everything that they tell us is
a lie
you know they tell us that their weapons
of mass destruction that was a lie
they tell us that there are no secret
prisons that was a lie they tell us that
there was no torture program that was a
lie
so why should we believe anything they
say we have to question everything
it doesn't matter who's in the white
house it doesn't matter if it's a
democrat or a republican they're all
guilty of the same thing so it's up to
us to keep up the fight
we can't let these last 20 years
go for naught
we have to make sure that people
understand that there are americans like
us who stand for peace and justice that
we will fight against these unnecessary
illegal wars we will stand up for human
rights and civil rights and civil
liberties and we will not give up
i apologize for my for my audio and my
my video thanks to everybody and enjoy
the rest of the event
bravo thank you very much john and um
thanks for the shout out to the youth
and i i put some information in the chat
to corroborate um your feelings on it
thank you very much